Guide to the Charles Wilkes Papers, 1816-1876 RL.01383
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Slaves. Hiring of. District of Columbia. Washington 1852 Oct. 5; 1854 Dec. 14; 1854 Dec. 15.
Slaves. Hiring of. North Carolina 1850 Jan. 1; 1850 Jan. 14; 1850 Jan. 31; 1850 Feb. 8; 1850 June 20; 1853 Nov. 1; 1856 Aug. 26; 1857 Jan. 3.
Slaves. Punishment of 1850 Jan. 31; 1850 Feb. 8.
Slaves. South Carolina 1826 Feb. 22; 1847 Nov. 28; 1857 Dec. 1; 1857 Dec. 13.
Slaves in Mining Printed Material: 1852 May 22
Slidell, John 1846 Apr. 3
Slidell, John [?] 1837 Jan. 7; 1837 Feb. 4.
Smith, Albert (1793-1867) 1843 Jan. 14
Smith, Joseph (1790-1877) 1838 Apr. 13; 1838 Sept. 30.
Smith, Junius 1851 Nov. 3
Smith, Margaret (Bayard) 1828 Nov. 14
Smith, Truman Letter to: 1864 Apr. 11
Smithsonian Institution 1848 Nov. 8; 1849 Mar. 22; 1850 Feb. 1; 1850 Mar. 4; 1850 June 23.
Smuggling 1848 Feb. 21
Smyth, Thomas 1850 July 20
Smyth, William Henry 1850 Aug. 26; 1859 May 2.
Snow, William Parker Clipping: 1861 Feb. 9 (attached to letter of 1862 Aug. 6
Snowden, James Ross 1857 Mar. 20
Soap Industry and Trade 1850 Oct. 29
Society Islands. Descriptiona and Travel 1839 Sept. 12
Society Islands. Missionaries, 1839 Sept. 12
Society Islands. Native Races, 1839 Sept. 12
South Africa. Constantia. Description and Travel 1852 Apr. 30
South Africa. History. Kafir Wars, 1811-1878 1852 Apr. 30
South Carolina. Aiken 1855 Oct. 27; 1855 Nov. 3.
South Carolina. Beaufort. Description and Travel 1838 Jan. 19
South Carolina. Charleston. Civil War, 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22); Clipping: Undated (attached to letter of 1862 Dec. 14).
South Carolina. Charleston. Commerce, 1849 Nov. 17
South Carolina. Charleston. Description and Travel 1826 Feb. 19
South Carolina. Charleston. Diseases. Yellow Fever 1849 Oct. 12
South Carolina. Charleston. Fire, 1838, 1838 Feb. 22
South Carolina. Charleston. Houses, 1837 Dec. 21
South Carolina. Charleston County. Description and Travel 1848 Feb. 22
South Carolina. Description and Travel, 1848 Apr. 15
South Carolina. Elections 1848 Oct. 10
South Carolina. Fort McAllister, 1863 Feb. 22
South Carolina. Legislature, 1830 June 20
South Carolina. Militia 1833 July 28
South Carolina. Plantations, 1826 Feb. 22; 1851 Nov. 3.
South Carolina. Planters 1826 Feb. 22
South Carolina. Political Conventions, 1830 June 20
South Carolina. Politics and Government 1830 June 20; 1833 July 28.
South Carolina. Population 1838 Jan. 19
South Carolina. Recreation 1826 Feb. 22
South Carolina. Rhett Family, 1860 Nov. 8
South Carolina. Rice Culture, 1848 Dec. 30
South Carolina. Roads 1826 Feb. 22
South Carolina. Secession 1848 Nov. 6; 1850 May 7; 1851 Feb. 5; 1861 Feb. 6.
South Carolina. Slaveowners, 1838 Jan. 19
South Carolina. Slaves 1826 Feb. 22; 1847 Nov. 28; 1857 Dec. 1; 1857 Dec. 13.
South Carolina. Social Life and Customs 1837 Dec. 25; 1837 Dec. 29.
South Carolina. State Rights, 1850 May 7
South Carolina. Tea Growing, 1851 Nov. 3
South Pole 1842 Oct. 18; 1842 Nov. 2.
Southard, Samuel Lewis 1828 Nov. 14; 1829 Jan. 2; 1829 Jan. 11.
Southern States. Cotton Growing, 1849 May 16
Southern States. Northern Opinion, 1837 Dec. 21; 1849 Jan. 21.
Southerners 1856 Dec. 21
Spain. Foreign Relations. United States 1863 Jan. 30 (2); 1872 Jan. 10.
Speculation in Land 1836 June 19
Spofford, Ainsworth Rand 1870 July 15; 1870 July 19; 1870 July 23; 1870 July 26; 1871 Jan. 24; 1871 Mar. 21; 1871 May 12; 1871 Aug. 9; 1873 Jan. 30; 1874 Jan. 24; 1874 May 18; 1874 July 1.
Squier, Ephraim George 1849 May 5
Stagecoach Travel 1825[?] Aug. 5; 1852 Jan. 7.
Stagecoach Travel. New York 1834 Oct. 13
Stagecoaches. France 1830 Dec. 21
Stahel, Julius 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22)
Stamp Mills 1849 June 12
Stansbury, Howard 1836 May 24
State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1854 Mar. 10
State Rights. South Carolina 1850 May 7
Stationary. Pictorial 1852 Aug. 30 (American Hotel, Cleveland, Ohio); 1854 Oct. 30 (M'Lure House, Wheeling, West Virginia); 1856 Jan. 3 (The Seal of the Chamber of Commerce of New York); 1856 Feb. 21 (Portrait of Benjamin Franklin); 1860 Oct. 3 (French's Hotel, New York, NY)
Steam Boilers. Marine 1852 Jan. 10; 1852 Nov. 17; 1853 Jan. [?]; 1853 Sept. 7.
Steamboat Disasters 1852 Nov. 13
Steamboat Travel 1825[?] Aug. 5; 1825[?]; 1852 Aug. 31; Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapters IV, V, IX, X).
Steamboat Travel. New York 1825[?] June
Steamboats 1846 Feb. 11; 1846 Feb. 17; 1852 Aug. 20; 1853 Jan. [?].
Steamboats. Algiers 1830 Aug. 19
Stevens, Isaac Ingalls 1853 Mar. 20; 1854 Mar. 18.
Stevens, Thomas Holdup (1819-1896), 1862[?] Sept. 30
Stewart, Charles (1778-1869), 1825 Mar. 24; 1825 Aug. 5[?]; 1825 Aug. 19; 1827 Mar. 8[?]; 1838 Jan. 18.
Stock Exchange. Philadelphia Printed Material: 1863 May 4
Stocks 1827 Mar. 12; 1844 Dec. 12; Miscellany: 1865 [?].
Stockton, Robert Field Letter to: 1853 Oct. 18; 1849 June 7; 1855 Apr. 17; 1855 Apr. 19; 1855 Apr. 22; 1855 Apr. 29; 1855 May 5; 1855 May 13; 1855 May 20; 1855 Aug. 24; 1855 Dec. 15; 1856 Jan. 2; 1856 Jan. 19; 1856 Feb. 24; 1856 Mar. 16; 1856 Mar. 31; 1856 May 4; 1856 Aug. 3; 1
Stoneman, George 1863 May 8
Storer, George W. [?] 1830 July 17; 1830 Aug. 9; 1830 Aug. 19; 1830 Aug. 25; 1830 Nov. 9; 1830 Dec. 6; 1830 Dec. 21; 1850 Mar. 16.
Stringham, Silas Horton [?], 1843 Jan. 8; 1843 Dec. 9; 1843 Dec. 18; 1843 Dec. 25; 1844 Feb. 9; 1844 Feb. 155.
Stuart, James Ewell Brown 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22); 1863 May 8.
Sugar. Manufacture and Refining. China, 1851 Nov. 17
Sugar. Manufacture and Refining. Venezuela, 1848 July 6
Sullivant, William Starling, 1849 June 11; 1856 Nov. 25; 1856 Dec. 3; 1856 Dec. 15; 1857 Jan. 28; 1857 Sept. 10; 1857 Sept. 24; 1857 Sept. 29; 1860 Jan. 3.
Sully, Thomas 1844 Mar. 2
Sulpher Mines and Mining. North Carolina, 1867 Mar. 5
Sumner, Edwin Vose 1863 Jan. 28
Sunbury[?] and Erie Railroad, 1859 July 11
Sunday Schools. New York 1854 Sept. 13
Support (Domestic Relations) 1836 Jan. 29
Surveying. Instruments 1848 Feb. 21
Surveys 1836 May 1; 1838 Feb. 26; 1838 Dec. 10; 1843 Mar. 5; 1843 Mar. 6; 1843 Mar. 13; 1843 Mar. 18; 1843 Mar. 26; 1843 Apr. 14; 1843 July 21; 1843 Oct. 27.
Swain, David Lowry 1857 May 24
Swimming 1848 July
Tableaux 1850s Aug. 27
Talcott, Andrew 1843 Jan. 22; 1843 May 5; 1843 July 21; 1843 Aug. 16; 1844 July 26.
Tallmadge, Frederick Augustus, 1849 Apr. 28
Tappan, Benjamin (1773-1857), 1847 June 24; 1857 May 27.
Tariff 1846 Aug. 6
Taylor, George (1820-1894) [?], 1855 May 20
Taylor, Margaret MacKall (Smith), 1849 Mar. 17
Taylor, Zachary. Inauguration, 1849 Mar. 6; 1849 Mar. 18[?].
Tea Growing. South Carolina 1851 Nov. 3
Tea Trade 1850 Sept. 2
Telescope 1837 Nov. 30
Temple, Henry John, Third Viscount Palmerston 1850 May 22
Ten Eyck, Anthony 1848 Dec. 12; 1849 Apr. 13; 1850 June 23.
Texas. History. Revolution, 1835-1836, 1836 May 5
Theater. Italy. Florence 1830 Nov. 9
Theater. Italy. Naples. Fonda 1830 Oct. 25
Theater. New York. New York Writings: "Theaters"
Theaters. Opera Houses. Italy. Naples. Opera of St. Carlos 1830 Oct. 12
Theaters. Opera Houses. New York 1849 May 16
Theory of the Winds 1859 July 26; 1859 Nov. 21.
Thompson, James Letters to: 1849 Dec. 26; 1850 Feb. 23.
Thouvenel, Edouard Antoine Writings: "In difesa del San Giacinto"
"Thumb, Tom" (Charles Sherwood Stratton) 1863 Feb. 22
Thurman, John Richardson 1849 Dec. 8 (on letter of Dec. 5)
Tobacco Manufacture and Trade. North Carolina. Charlotte 1876 Feb. 21
Toombs, Robert Augustus 1849 Dec. 21
Torches 1848 Apr. 12; 1848 Apr. 13.
Torpedoes 1862 Aug. 9; 1862 Aug. 23.
Torrey, John 1849 Oct. 24; 1857 Jan. 28; 1857 Sept. 10; 1859 Aug. 1; 1860 Jan. 3; 1860 July 11; 1870 July 26; 1873 Jan. 30.
Toucey, Isaac Letter to: 1857 Apr. 21; 1852 Aug. 24.
Toucey, Isaac [?] 1849[?], Feb.; 1857 May 24.
Trade Winds 1848 Apr. 25
Trees Miscellany: 1849 Mar.
Trent Affair 1862 Jan. 16; 1862 Feb. 5; 1862 June 14; 1863 Apr. 19; Writings: "The great international question"; Writings: "The Surrender of Mason and Slidell"; Writings: "In difesa del San Giacinto".
Trumbull, John (1756-1843) 1818[?] Jan. 20; 1825[?] Apr. 4; 1827 Mar. 12.
Trumbull family 1871 Dec. 10
Tuckerman, Edward Letter to: 1849 July 9; 1849 June 29; 1849 July 5; 1857 Dec. 24; 1860 Jan. 3.
Tunis. Antiquities. Carthage, 1830 Sept. 12
Tunis. Aqueducts 1830 Sept. 12
Tunis. Bardo 1830 Sept. 12
Tunis. Bey 1830 Sept. 12
Tunis. Camels 1830[?] Sept. 3
Tunis. Cemeteries 1830 Sept. 12
Tunis. Cisterns 1830 Sept. 12
Tunis. Clothing and Dress 1830[?] Sept. 3
Tunis. Date 1830[?] Sept. 3
Tunis. Description and Travel, 1830 Sept. 3; 1830 Sept. 12; 1830 Sept. 18.
Tunis. United States. Diplomatic and Consular Service 1830[?] Sept. 3
Tunis. English in 1830 Sept. 18
Tunis. Food 1830 Sept. 18
Tunis. La Goulette 1830[?] Sept. 3
Tunis. Lake of Tunis 1830[?] Sept. 3
Tunis. Maps 1830[?] Sept. 3
Tunis. Palaces 1830 Sept. 3; 1830 Sept. 12.
Tunis. Politics and Government, 1830[?] Sept. 3; 1830 Sept. 12.
Tunis. Social Life and Customs, 1830 Sept. 12
Tunis. Tunis (City). Description and Travel 1830[?] Sept. 3
Turks 1830[?] Sept. 3
Turnbull, Alex 1830 Dec. 21; 1830 Dec. 25.
Turnbull, Robert James 1827 Mar. 12
Turpentine Industry and Trade. North Carolina 1853 Mar. 31
Turrill, Joel 1848 Dec. 12; 1849 Apr. 13.
Turtle Islands 1856 Feb. 2; 1856 Feb. 7.
Twiggs, David Emanuel 1848 Jan. 1
Tyler, John (1790-1862)m 1842 ca. Mar. 18; 1842 June 20; 1842 June 22; 1842 July 22.
Typhoons 1850 July 24
Union Mining Company 1854 Jan. 28; 1857 Jan. 11.
United States. Army. Civil War. 1862 Aug. 21 (enclosed with letter of Aug. 22); Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20.
United States. Army. Civil War. Appointment and Promotions 1863 Mar. 10; 1863 Mar. 14.
United States. Army. Civil War. Drill and Minor Tactics 1863 June 9
United States. Army. Civil War. Negro Troops 1863 Jan. 30; 1863 Feb. 8.
United States. Army. Civil War. Officers 1863 Feb. 8
United States. Army. Civil War. Armies. Army of the Potomac 1862 Dec. 11; 1862 Dec. 16; 1863 Jan. 18; 1863 Jan. 27; 1863 Feb. 11; 1863 Feb. 12; 1863 Feb. 22; 1863 Mar. 15; 1863 Mar. 27; 1863 Apr. 1; 1863 May 8; 1863 May 28; 1863 May 29; Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20.
United States. Army. Civil War. Corps. V 1864 June 1
United States. Army. Civil War. Corps. VI 1863 May 8
United States. Army. Civil War. Regiments. Connecticut. Artillery. 1st Heavy 1863 June 9
United States. Army. Civil War. Regiments. New York. Infantry. 121st Regiment[?], 1863 May 20
United States. Army. Corps of Topographical Engineers 1842 Dec. 5
United States. Army. Creek War [?], 1836 Jan. 22
United States. Army. Mexican War. Battalions. Louisiana. Infantry 1848 Jan. 1
United States. Army. Mexican War. Regiments. Artillery. 4th 1848 Jan. 1
United States. Army. Mexican War. Regiments[?]. Louisiana. Cavalry. Louisiana Mounted Men, 1848 Jan. 1
United States. Army. Officers, 1837[?] June 25
United States. Army. Regiments. Infantry. 3rd 1851 Jan. 27
United States. Army. Regiments. Infantry. 7th 1849 Sept. 30
United States. Coast and Geodetic Survey 1843 Mar. 13; 1843 Dec. 9; 1844 May; 1849 Mar. 17.
United States. Congress. Joint Committee on the Library 1845 Feb. 4; 1845 Feb. 9; 1850 May 23; 1871 Jan. 24; 1871 Mar. 21; 1874 May 1; 1874 May 18; 1874 May 25; 1875 Apr. 5; Miscellany: 1852 June 14; Miscellany: 1857 Dec. 26.
United States. Congress. Senate, 1826 Jan. 26; 1826 Mar. 26; 1856 Feb. 9; 1859 Feb. 4; 1860 Nov. 23; 1863 Feb. 25; 1863 Mar. 10; 1871 Mar. 21.
United States. Congress. House of Representatives 1844[?]; 1871 Mar. 21.
United States. Congress 1837 Sept. 2; 1849 Dec. 21; 1850 July 1; 1852 Oct. 27; 1863 Feb. 24 (enclosed with letter of Feb. 25); 1863 Feb. 28; 1863 Mar. 14; 1870 July 15; 1870 July 19.
United States. Capitol 1871 Mar. 21
United States. Department of the Navy, 1849 Mar. 10; 1863 Apr. 4; Miscellany: 1862 [?].
United States. Department of the Navy. Officials and Employees 1849 Dec. 21; 1850 Mar. 28; 1850 Oct. 2; Miscellany: 1862 [?](2); Miscellany: Undated.
United States. Depot of Charts and Instruments [?] 1837[?] June 25; 1838 Jan. 8 (2); 1838 Jan. 13.
United States. Description and Travel, Writings: Trip to the Far West
United States. Diplomatic and Consular Service. Trinidad, Cuba [?] 1863 Apr. 11
United States. Diplomatic and Consular Service. Tunis 1830[?] Sept. 3
United States. Economic Conditions 1837 Sept. 2
United States. Foreign Relations. Formosa 1851 July 20
United States. Foreign Relations. Great Britain 1838 Jan. 6; 1862 Jan. 16; Writings: "The Surrender of Mason and Slidell"; Writings: "The great international question"; Writings: "In difesa del San Giacinto".
United States. Foreign Relations. Hawaii 1850 July 12; 1851 Mar. 28.
United States. Foreign Relations. Mexico 1846 Apr. 3
United States. Panama. Foreign Relations 1826 Mar. 17
United States. Foreign Relations. Spain 1863 Jan. 30 (2); 1872 Jan. 10.
United States. Hydrographic Office, 1870 Aug. 25
United States. Immigration Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVII, pp. 246-247
United States. Laws, Statutes, Etc. H.R. Bill No. 535 Printed Material: 1864 June 18
United States. Laws, Statutes, Etc. H.R. Bill No. 801 Printed Material: 1865 Mar. 1
United States. Laws, Statutes, Etc. Reconstruction Acts, 1867-1868 1867 Feb. 21; 1867 Mar. 4.
United States. Library of Congress, 1849 Oct. 26
United States. Marine Corps, 1852 July 24; 1857 June 2; 1857 June 4; 1863 Jan. 30; Miscellany: Undated.
United States. Mint 1854 Apr. 2; 1857 Mar. 11; 1857 Mar. 20.
United States. Mint. New York, 1846 Jan. 20; 1846 Jan. 25; 1846 Feb. 3.
United States. Naval Lyceum 1856 Apr. 7
United States. Navy 1826 Mar. 26; 1836 Mar. 14; 1838 Jan. 3; 1838 Jan. 6; 1842 Sept. 24; 1846 Feb. 11; 1846 Feb. 17; 1849 May 21; 1850 Oct. 21; 1850 Dec. 3; 1851 Jan. 27; 1851 Sept. 15[?]; 1859 Oct. 21; 1862 [?] (3); 1860s[?]; Miscellany: Undated.
United States. Navy. Appointments and Promotions 1826 Jan. 26; 1826 Mar. 26; 1829 Jan. 2; 1838 Jan. 3; 1838 Jan. 6; 1838 May 11; 1838 July 19; 1838 [?] (3); 1839 Feb. 23; 1839 Mar. 31; 1839 [?]; 1842 Feb. 20; 1842 Mar. (scattered); 1842 June (scattered); 1848 Feb. 29; 1848 Mar. 2; 1848 Mar. 10; 1849 Mar
United States. Navy. Civil War, 1862 Aug. 21; 1863 Feb. 3; 1863 Apr. 4; Miscellany: 1862 [?].
United States. Navy. Civil War. Appointments and Promotions 1862 Dec. 5; 1862 Dec. 12; 1862 Dec. 14; 1862 Dec. 17; 1862 Dec. 24 (enclosed with letter of Dec. 28); 1863 Jan. 5; 1863 Jan. 9; 1863 Jan. 12; 1863 Jan. 19; 1863 Jan. 23; 1863 Jan. 26; 1863 Jan. 27; 1863 Jan. 28; 1863 Jan. 30; 1863 Feb. 4; 1863 Feb. 10; 1
United States. Navy. Civil War. Desertion 1862 Aug. 27; Printed Material: 1864 June 18.
United States. Navy. Civil War. Discharges 1862 Aug. 7
United States. Navy. Civil War. Food, 1862 Aug. 12
United States. Navy. Civil War. Health Conditions 1862 July 26
United States. Navy. Civil War. Medical and Sanitary Affairs 1862 Aug. 5; 1862 Aug. 12.
United States. Navy. Civil War. Orders, 1862 Dec. 12
United States. Navy. Civil War. Ordnance Miscellany: 1862 [?]
United States. Navy. Civil War. Pay, Allowances, Etc. Printed Material: 1865 Mar. 1
United States. Navy. Civil War. Retirements 1863 Mar. 6; Miscellany: 1862 [?].
United States. Navy. Civil War. Ships, 1862 Aug. 1; 1862 Aug. 5; 1862 Aug. 7; 1862 Aug. 12 (2); 1862 Oct. 29; 1862 Dec. 12; Miscellany: 1862 [?] (2).
United States. Navy. Civil War. Surgeons 1862 Aug. 5
United States. Navy. Civil War. Uniforms 1863 May 19
United States. Navy. Civil War. Units. James River Flotilla 1862 July 24; 1862 July 26; 1862 Aug. 1; 1862 Aug. 5 (2); 1862 Aug. 6; 1862 Aug. 12.
United States. Navy. Civil War. Squadrons. West India 1863 June 4
United States. Navy. Cruises, 1822 Feb. 7; 1822 Feb. 13; 1822 Mar. 23; 1823 Jan.[?]; 1830 July-1831 May (letters of Charles Wilkes); Scattered Letters of John Wilkes (1827-1908): 1845 Nov.-1846 Sept.; Scattered Letters of John Wilkes (1827-1908):1847 Oct.-1848 July; Scattered Letters
United States. Navy. Discipline, 1838 Sept. 26; 1838 Oct. 21; 1838 Dec. 5; 1839 Feb. 23 (2); 1839 Mar. 31; 1839 June 12; 1839 Sept. 12; 1840 Mar. 7; 1840 Oct. 2; 1840 Oct. 13; 1840 early Dec.[?]; 1841 May 20; 1841 Nov. 27; 1847 Dec. 11; 1849 Mar. 19; 1849 Mar. 20; 1849; 1850 Mar. 28; 185
United States. Navy. Dress and Appearance 1838 Sept. 26; 1838 Oct. 21.
United States. Navy. Food 1839 June 12
United States. Navy. Guards, 1852 July 24
United States. Navy. Health Conditions, 1847 Nov. 30; 1850 May 17 (on letter of May 23); 1850 July 24.
United States. Navy. Midshipmen, 1850 Mar. 28
United States. Navy. Officers, 1830[?] Sept. 3; 1830 Dec. 6; 1837 June 30; 1837 Dec. 25; 1838 Feb. 26; 1838 ca. July; 1838 Sept. 2; 1838 Sept. 16; 1838 Nov. 25; 1838 Dec. 10; 1840 Mar. 7; 1845 June 11; 1845 July 7; 1848 June 18.
United States. Navy. Officers. Papers of Wilkes Family Papers: 1816-1876 (Papers of Charles Wilkes)
United States. Navy. Ordnance, 1847 Mar. 8; 1865 May 20.
United States. Navy. Pay, Allowances, Etc. 1830s; 1843 Aug. 21; 1852 Apr. 19; 1870 Aug. 13.
United States. Navy. Postal Service, 1848 May 31
United States. Navy. Retirements, 1850 June 23; 1870 Sept. 13; 1870 Sept. 29; 1871 Jan. 24; Miscellany: Undated.
United States. Navy. Sailors' Letters, 1845 June-1846 Sept. (scattered); 1847 Jan.-Aug. (scattered); 1848 Jan.-July (scattered); Letters of John Wilkes (1827-1908).
United States. Navy. Ship Life, 1822 Feb. 7; 1830 July 7; 1830 July 17; 1831 Jan. 30.
United States. Navy. Ships 1847 Dec. 21; Miscellany: 1859 [?]; Miscellany: Undated.
United States. Navy. Squadrons. East India 1850 Oct. 2
United States. Navy. Mexican War, 1846 Sept. 21
United States. Patent Office, 1844 Dec. 31; 1849 Apr. 27; 1849 Apr. 28 (2); 1849 Apr. 30; 1849 May 1; 1849 May 6; 1849 May 14; 1851 Oct. 13.
United States. Politics and Government, 1850 July 1
United States. Slavery 1834 July 16; 1850 Feb. 3; 1851 Jan. 15.
United States. Slavery. Northern Opinion 1848 Apr. 14
United States. Supreme Court, 1849 Feb. 16
United States Exploring Expedition, 1838-1842 1828 Mar. 18; 1829 Jan. 2; 1829 Jan. 11; 1829 May 7; 1836 July 18-1837 June 10 (scattered); 1837 Dec.-1841 Nov. (letters of Charles Wilkes); 1842 Feb. 20; 1842 Aug. 28; 1842 Dec.-1845 Feb. (scattered); 1848 Mar. 13; 1848 Sept. 27; 1848 Nov. 12; 1849-1857
Universities and Colleges. Columbia College [?]. New York. New York 1849 May 8
Universities and Colleges. Columbia University. New York. New York Writings: Untitled, pp. 6-9
Universities and Colleges. Dickinson College. Pennsylvania. Carlisle 1855 Apr. 5
Upshur, Abel Parker Letter to: 1842 Mar. 18; 1842 Mar. 4; 1842 Mar. 18 (2); 1842 Mar. 21; 1842 June 16; 1842 June 27; 1842 July 22; 1843 Aug. 4; 1843 Aug. 16; 1849 Mar. 10.
Upshur, George P. 1847 Mar. 10; 1847 June 6; 1848 Jan. 27; 1848 Mar. 31.
Upton, Emory 1862 Oct. 7; 1862 Oct. 17; 1863 Apr. 1; 1863 Apr. 14 (part of letter of Apr. 13); 1863 Apr. 14; 1863 Apr. 23; 1863 May 8; 1863 May 20; 1864 June 1.
Vallandigham, Clement Laird, 1863 May 22
Van Allen, James Henry 1862 Dec. 4
Van Buren, John (1810-1866) [?], 1830 July 13
Van Buren, Martin Letter to: 1826 Feb. 18; 1833 July 28; 1837 May 16; 1838 Jan. 6; 1838 Jan. 22; 1838 Aug. 18; 1838 (?, #136).
Vandenhoff, George 1863 Jan. 23
Vaughan, Sir Charles Richard, 1825 Aug. 19
Venezuela. Caracas. Description and Travel 1848 May 31; 1848 July 6.
Venezuela. Caracas. Earthquakes, 1848 May 31
Venezuela. Caracas. Massacres, 1848 May 31
Venezuela. Elections 1848 June 18
Venezuela. Manufacture and Refining. Sugar 1848 July 6
Venezuela. Politics and Government, 1848 July 6
Venezuela. Social Life and Customs, 1848 May 31
Verplanck, Gulian Crommelin, 1834 Apr. 12
Vincennes Island 1839 Sept. 12
Virgin Islands. Saint Thomas, 1848 May 6
Virginia. Drewry's Bluff. Fortifications Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 1; Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 25.
Virginia. Fort Darling. Fortifications, Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 25
Virginia. Fort Monroe 1862 Aug. 21 (enclosed with letter of Aug. 22)
Virginia. Gold Mines and Mining, 1853 Oct. 23; 1854 Jan. 28.
Virginia. Gold Mines and Mining. Vancluse Mine 1849 Nov. 30; 1853 Oct. 23.
Virginia. Petersburg. Civil War, Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 25
Virginia. Railroads 1865 June 20
Virginia. Richmond. Civil War, Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 1
Virginia. Secession 1861 Feb. 6
Virginia [?]. Warrenton. Civil War, 1862 Nov. 14
Virginia. Yorktown. Civil War, 1862 Aug. 21 (enclosed with letter of Aug. 22)
Voorhees, Philip Falkerson [?], 1838 Jan. 8; 1838 Jan. 13; 1850 Apr. 21; 1850 June 23; 1850 July 24; 1850 Sept. 14; 1850 Oct. 2.
Voyages Around the World Map: 1856 (In Picture Cabinet III-3)
Voyages of the US Exploring Expedition Legal Papers: 1849 Oct. 1
Waddell, Alfred Moore 1874 Feb. 3; 1876 Feb. 21.
Wadsworth, Alexander S. [?], 1830 Oct. 4; 1830 Oct. 12; 1830 Dec. 6; 1830 Dec. 8; 1831 Jan. 30; 1837 June 29[?].
Wages. Agricultural. North Carolina, 1857 Nov. 22
Wages. Blacksmiths. North Carolina 1854 Jan. 10; 1854 Feb. 1; 1854 Dec. 31; 1857 Jan. 3.
Wages. Carpenters. North Carolina 1854 Jan. 18; 1854 Jan. 28.
Wages. Gold Miners. North Carolina 1849 Feb. 17; 1849 Mar. 21.
Wages. Millwrights. North Carolina 1854 Feb. 1
Wages. Negroes. North Carolina 1854 Jan. 13; 1854 Mar. 5.
Wages. North Carolina 1849 Jan. 30; 1849 Feb. 6; 1849 Mar. 21; 1849 Apr. 4; 1849 June 12; 1854 Jan. 10; 1854 Mar. 5.
Wages. Stonemasons. North Carolina 1854 Jan. 18
Walbridge, Hiram 1853 July 16; 1853 July 21; 1853 July 22 (2); 1853 July 23; 1853 July 24; 1853 July 26; 1853 Aug. 4; 1856 Mar. 25; 1856 Aug. 3.
Walker, John (North Carolina Senator), 1861 Jan. 2
Walker, Robert John Letter to: 1849 Jan. 2 (enclosed with letter of 1849 Jan. 5)
Walker, William 1859 Oct. 21
Walsh Robert [?] 1836 Oct. 15
Wardwell, Daniel 1836 Mar. 31
War of 1812. Campaigns and Battles. Lake Erie, Battle of, 1813 Sept. 10 1853 Aug. 31
Warrington, Lewis 1837 May 16; 1838 Sept. 16; 1838 Dec. 10; 1838 Dec. 18; 1849 May 25.
Warships 1838 June 18
Washburn, Cadwallader Colden, 1870 Aug. 25
Water Supply. District of Columbia 1860 Jan. 12
Water Supply. New York. New York Writings: Crotan Water Works"
Webb, James Watson [?] 1836 Feb. 19
Webster, Daniel 1842 July 15; 1842 Nov. 2; 1843 Mar. 26; 1843 Dec. 22; 1850 Apr. 19; 1852 Mar. 1; 1852 May 3 (with letter of same date).
Webster, Daniel [?] 1847 Dec. 18
Weddings. District of Columbia. Washington, 1836 July 2
Weddings. New York 1830 Nov. 11
Welles, Gideon Letter to: 1862 July 26; Letter to: 1862 Aug. 7; Letter to: 1862 Dec.; Telegram to: 1862 Aug. 7; 1862 Sept. 24; 1862 Nov. 23; 1862 Dec. 16; 1862 Dec. 21; 1862 Dec. 21 (on verso of letter of Dec. 24, enclosed with letter of Dec. 28); 1863 Jan. 19; 1863 Jan
Welles, Mary Jane (Hale) 1863 May 28
Western America 1849 Jan. 15-Feb. (scattered); 1849 Mar. 2; 1849 Mar. 12; 1849 Apr. 20; 1849 Aug. 18; 1849 Sept. 4; 1849 Sept. 11.
Whalers 1850 Dec. 3
West Virginia. Wheeling. Hotels. M'Lure House 1854 Oct. 30
Western States. Migration. Internal, 1836 June 19; 1857 Nov. 29.
Wheat. Chile 1826 Feb. 4
Wheat. Harvesting 1855 June 29
Wheat. North Carolina 1858 July 5
Wheat Trade 1858 May 9; 1860 Jan. 2.
White, Campbell P. 1830 Aug. 19
Wilkes, Charles (1798-1877), Letters to: 1818 Jan. 8-1876 May 12
Wilkes, John (1827-1908) Letter to: 1838[?] Nov.; Letter to: 1839 June 2; Letter to: 1840 Mar. 10; Letter to: 1840 Oct.; Letter to: 1844 Apr. 25 (enclosed with letter of Apr. 26); Letter to: 1848 Nov. 9; Letter to: 1849 Mar. 21; Letter to: 1849 May 29; Letter to: 1849 June 25; Le
William, Prince of Württemberg, 1850 Oct. 21
Winds 1848 Jan. 27; 1856 Jan. 19; 1856 Jan. 28; 1856 Jan. 29; 1856 Feb. 8; 1856 Feb. 15; Map: 1856 (In Picture Cabinet III-3).
Winslow, Warren 1859 May 18
Winthrop, Robert Charles [?], 1845 Feb. 4; 1852 Aug. 9.
Wisconsin. Immigration 1836 June 19
Wisconsin. Milwaukee. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter IV)
Wisconsin. Prairie du Chien. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter IX)
Wisconsin. Prescott. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapters V and IX)
Wisconsin. Racine. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter IV)